• Network Advertising Initiative• Digital Advertising Alliance• Interactive Advertising Bureau

The tracking data we record includes, without limitation, Information regarding the number and frequencyof users to the Website, the websites that users access before and after they visit the Website, the

D A T A   P R IVA C Y POLICY \& TERMS OF USE

(Last Up d a t e d : Ma r c h   1 0,   2 021)

Pencils of Promise, Inc. (“PoP”, “we”, “us” or “our”) shares your concern about theprotection of your personal information online. This Privacy Policy and Terms of Use (“Policy”) is our policyregarding maintaining the privacy of personal information we collect online and regarding our content andonline relationship with you in connection with our online properties, including, without limitation, www.

pencilsofpromise.org (the “Website”).

This Policy describes the privacy practices we undertake, the data we collect, how we secure that data,and how long we retain that data. It also includes the terms of use governing the Website. By using theWebsite, you agree to abide by the terms of this Policy. This Policy applies regardless of how you accessour Website – whether by personal computers, mobile devices or otherwise.

The General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) is a European Regulation concerning the use andprocessing of personal information. We are committed to processing your information in compliance withthe GDPR upon its effectiveness on May 25, 2018.

BY VISITING THIS WEBSITE, YOU CONSENT TO OUR USING ANY INFORMATION THAT YOU PROVIDE TOUS OR THAT WE COLLECT IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS POLICY. IFYOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS POLICY, DO NOT VISIT OR USE THIS WEBSITE.

Information We Collect and Track. PoP collects and retains two types of information about Websitevisitors: (i) personal information that individual visitors provide when interacting on the Website,or voluntarily at certain other points (such as via forms or e- mails); and (ii) tracking data, which isautomatically collected from every Website visitor, (collectively, “Information”). The Information that wegather may include your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, birth date or other elementsof personal information.

In addition, if you contact us, we may keep a record of your correspondence, including any Informationcontained therein.

It is up to you whether or not you want to provide us with Information. When we ask you to provideInformation, you can decline and still visit the Website to learn more about us and what we do. However, ifyou choose not to provide Information to us, you may be unable to contribute to our charitable mission.

We also use a third party to gather information on how you and others are using the Website. By usingthis service we are able (for example) to see how many people visited a given page or clicked on agiven link. We use tracking pixels to serve ads through third party network services to people who havevisited our Website (“Retargeting Ads”). The tracking pixel is a piece of JavaScript code for our websitethat enables us to measure, optimize, and build audiences for our marketing campaigns. The trackingpixels allow us to track actions users take after viewing our ads across multiple devices, includingmobile phones, tablets and desktop computers and will continue to monitor the actions they take afterclicking on our ad. To learn more about related practices or how to opt-out from receiving retargetedadvertisements and remove tracking technologies from your device,please visit:

Internet software used by our users to access the Website, and our users’ IP addresses and Internetservice providers.

Your Rights and Preferences. We are committed to honoring your right to privacy. With this in mind, itis important that we inform you of certain rights available to you with respect to the Information that youprovide to us.

• Right of Access – your right to be informed of and request access to your Information;

• Right to Rectification – your right to request that we amend or update your Information where it isinaccurate or incomplete;

• Right to Erasure – your right to request that we delete your Information;

• Right to Restrict – your right to request that we temporarily or permanently stop processing all orsome of your Information;

• Right to Object – your right to object to your Information being processed for direct marketingpurposes;

• Right to Data Portability – your right to request a copy of your Information in electronic formatand the corresponding right to transmit that Information for use elsewhere; and

• Right not to be Subject to Automated Decision-Making \- the right to not be subject to a decisionbased solely on automated decision making, including profiling, where the decision would have a legaleffect on you or produce a similarly significant effect.

It is important that you understand these rights and know that you are free to exercise each of them withrespect to your Information. If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us as describedbelow. In your request, please indicate (a) what Information is concerned, and (b) which of the aboverights you would like to enforce.

How We Use Your Information. The Information that we collect and that you provide to us is used forour purposes and the purpose for which you provided it, including, without limitation, to support ourcharitable mission and/or to respond to your requests or correspondence. This provides PoP with a lawfulbasis to collect and retain your Information and to analyze it so that we can serve you in the best mannerpossible on our Website through enhanced features and functions and to provide you with usefulinformation, including, without limitation, information from third parties.

We will not disclose any personally identifiable information to third parties, except (i) to parties whoperform services for us, such as sending you mail or e-mail, web hosting, credit card processing and othersimilar services; (ii) when we believe that such disclosure is required by law; (iii) to enforce this Policy; (iv)to protect the rights, property, security or safety of PoP, Website users or the public; (v) to respond to anemergency; or (vi) as otherwise stated in this Policy.

We use certain tracking data for several purposes, including, without limitation, for load balancing metricsand to create reports on user demographics and Website traffic patterns. The reports that are generatedfrom tracking data are used for a variety of purposes, including, for example, improving the Website andour services.

Analytics and Links to Third-Party Sites. We will not sell your Information or provide it to third partiesfor our own financial gain. In fact, we only share your Information when such sharing genuinely furthersour charitable mission. Nevertheless, we may employ third party agents or third party service providersto operate the Website and/or to perform functions on our behalf, such as processing donations or storepurchases, sending mail and e-mail, and analyzing data or other administrative tasks. These third partieshave access to the Information needed to perform their functions. We attempt to limit such third parties tousing the Information that is shared with them solely for the purpose of providing such services, however,we cannot be responsible for such third parties’ use of Information not in compliance with this Policy.

Some of the third parties with whom we work include:

• Hotjar – We use Hotjar in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service

and experience. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and

their devices (in particular device’s IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device

screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country

only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized

user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to matchit with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy at https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy.

• Constant Contact – We use Constant Contact to efficiently and securely distribute emails to a largelist of contacts. Data used in Constant Contact is sourced from Salesforce (mentioned below) and,therefore, if a Website user provides their contact information via the Website this same Information canbe used in Constant Contact. For further details, see Constant Contact’s Privacy Policy at https://www.

constantcontact.com/legal/privacy-notice.

• Segment – We use Segment as a means to transfer data to and from our other Website tools in

order to analyze that data efficiently in one location. For further details, please see Segment’s privacy

policy at https://segment.com/docs/legal/privacy/.

• Google Analytics and Ads – We use Google Analytics to gather information about how visitorsengage with our Website, how many visit, and other general user visitor information. For further details,please see Google Analytics’ privacy policy at www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.

• Social Media Widgets – Our Website includes social media features such as the Facebook “Like”button and Twitter “Follow” button. These features may collect your IP address, which page you arevisiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. These social mediafeatures are either hosted by a Third Party or hosted directly on our Website. Your interactions with thesefeatures are governed by the Privacy Policy of the social media company providing such services.

• Salesforce – We use Salesforce for data management, reporting and mass marketing. When youuse the forms on our Website – such as to receive emails from us, contact us, or to donate, Salesforcecollects that data. This can include basic contact information, preferences, giving history, and yourinteractions and communications with PoP. Other interactions with PoP outside of our Website may alsocontribute to information recorded in Salesforce, such as your attendance at PoP events, supporting PoPon third party giving platforms, and offline giving. For further details, please see Saleforce’s privacy policyat https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/.

• Classy – We use Classy for fundraising, event ticketing and direct donations. Classy collects basiccontact information, and billing and credit card information submitted by donors. This data is also sharedwith PoP and stored in our secure Salesforce database to help us manage your relationship and gifts toPoP and to communicate with you. For further details, please see Classy’s privacy policy at https://www.classy.org/terms/privacy.

• Other Donation Processing Vendors – We use various other third-parties to process donations to

our charitable mission. Data collected by these vendors is sent to our secure Salesforce database to help

us manage our relationship with our supporters. For further details, please contact us at the number and/or address at the end of this document.

We cannot control or be held responsible for third parties’ privacy practices and content. If you click ona link to a third-party website, any Information that you provide will not be covered by this Policy. Pleaseread any applicable privacy policies of the third-party website to find out how they collect and processyour Information.

How Your Information Is Protected. We take reasonable precautions to protect your Information fromloss, misuse or alteration. Personally identifiable information is stored on our server and is not publiclyaccessible. Further, personally identifiable information is only accessed by our employees on a “needto know” basis. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct useof information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures tosafeguard and secure the information we collect online. Additionally, sensitive data such as credit cardnumbers are encrypted using SSL and other industry standard measures, to provide an additional level ofsecurity.

Please note that no system is fully secure. Therefore, we encourage you to take all appropriate securitymeasures when providing us with Information – such as using and limiting access to your credit card andbanking information and access to your computers, personal electronic devices and web browsers.

Retention and Deletion of Your Information. We keep your Information only as long as necessary tosupport our charitable mission. As set forth above, you have various rights with respect to the retentionof your Information, including, but not limited to, the right to request that we delete your Information (bywriting to us at the physical address or email address supplied below). We will honor your request, unlesswe are legally allowed or required to maintain your Information – such as to (a) process any outstandingor unresolved charitable donation, (b) meet our legal, tax, audit or accounting obligations, (c) comply withlegal process or court order, and/or (d) protect the rights, property, security or safety of PoP, Websiteusers or the public; (e) respond to an emergency and/or (f) confirm your identity.

Ownership of Content. The Website includes a combination of content that we, our users and otherthird parties create (collectively, the “Content”). Except as noted on the Website, all of the Contentavailable through the Website, including, but not limited to, written content, interface design and layout,photographs, graphics, images, illustrations, marks, logos, sound or video clips, software code andanimation, is trademarked or copyright protected. Except as noted on the Website, you may not use, store,display, modify, reproduce, publish, transmit, participate in the transfer or sale of, create derivative worksof, distribute, publicly perform, publicly display, or in any way exploit any of the materials or Content onthe Website (including, for the avoidance of doubt, Content provided by our users) in whole or in part. Ifyou would like to request permission to use any of the Content on the Website, please contact us at info@

pencilsofpromise.org.

Pencils of Promise, Inc. is a registered trademark owned by PoP and may not be used or displayed withoutthe prior written consent of PoP. Other trademarks, service marks and names and logos appearing on theWebsite are the property of PoP, its affiliates or their respective owners. No right, title or interest in anyContent or in any trademark, service mark, name or logo appearing on the Website is transferred to youas a result of your use of the Website.

Posting and Transmitting Content. You are solely responsible for all materials, whether publicly postedor privately transmitted, that you submit, upload, e-mail, transmit or otherwise make available on theWebsite (“Your Content”). You represent and warrant that Your Content does not violate any right of anythird party, including, without limitation, copyright, trademark, privacy or other personal or proprietaryrights of any person or entity. You further represent and warrant that Your Content will not containlibelous or otherwise unlawful, abusive or obscene material (as determined by PoP in its sole discretion),or contain any computer virus or other malicious code that could in any way affect the operation of theWebsite or any computer that connects to the Website. You may not use false or misleading contactinformation, pretend to be someone other than yourself, or otherwise mislead PoP or its service providers.

You should be aware that Your Content may be read, collected or used by other Website visitors. We arenot responsible for the third party use of Your Content.

We have the right, but not the obligation, to remove any Content posted to the Website by users that may,in our sole discretion, violate this Policy or that is otherwise, in our sole opinion, objectionable.

Grant of License. You represent and warrant that you are the author of Your Content, that you own allintellectual property rights in and to Your Content and that no third party is entitled to any compensationor other payment in connection the exploitation by PoP of Your Content. PoP and its service providers willtreat such content posted, transmitted or

submitted by you as non-confidential and non-proprietary information. Upon posting, submitting ortransmitting Your Content on or through the Website, you grant PoP a worldwide, irrevocable, royalty-free,non-exclusive license, with the right to sublicense, use, reproduce, create derivative works of, distribute,publicly perform, publicly display, transfer, transmit, distribute, and publish Your Content and subsequentversions of Your Content for any and all purposes. Please do not send us or post any creative ideas orany other plans or proposals that you would like to keep confidential and proprietary. You agree that anyinformation that you provide us will be covered by the license granted herein.

Disclaimers. We disclaim any responsibility for the deletion, the failure to store, the misdelivery, or theuntimely delivery of any information or material submitted to or transmitted through the Website.

WE MAKE NO WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, WITHOUTLIMITATION, WARRANTIES OF TITLE OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESSFOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, WITH RESPECT TO THE WEBSITE, ANY CONTENT, OR ANY OF THESERVICES, TOOLS OR PRODUCTS AVAILABLE ON THE WEBSITE. YOU EXPRESSLY AGREE THAT YOUWILL ASSUME THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND THE PERFORMANCE OF THE WEBSITE ANDTHE ACCURACY OR COMPLETENESS OF ITS CONTENT.

Limitation of Liability. PoP and its officers, directors, employees, agents, service providers, andlicensors (collectively, the “PoP Parties”) shall not be liable for any direct, indirect, incidental, specialor consequential damages, resulting from the use or the inability to use the Website and services orresulting from any information or services obtained or messages received or transactions entered intothrough the Website or resulting from unauthorized access to or alteration of your transmissions of data,including but not limited to, damages for loss of profits, use, data or other intangibles, even if we havebeen advised of the possibility of such damages.Because some jurisdictions do not allow the exclusion or limitation of liability for consequential orincidental damages, in such states liability is limited to the fullest extent permitted by law.

If you are dissatisfied with any portion of this Website, or with this Policy, your sole and exclusive remedyis to discontinue using this Website.

Compliance With Laws. We reserve the right to disclose any Information to comply with any law,regulation, decree, judgment, order, subpoena or any other governmental order (“Order”) without anyobligation to contest or verify the accuracy of such Order.

Waiver of Jury Trial. THE PARTIES HEREBY IRREVOCABLY WAIVE ANY AND ALL RIGHT TO TRIAL BYJURY IN ANY LEGAL PROCEEDING ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO THIS AGREEMENT OR THETRANSACTIONS CONTEMPLATED HEREBY.

Injunctive Relief. You acknowledge that any use of the Website except as expressly permitted by thisPolicy will cause irreparable injury for which monetary damages would not be sufficient, and you consentto entry of immediate and permanent injunctive relief with respect to such unauthorized use.

Indemnification. By utilizing the Website and/or submitting Your Content, you agree to indemnify, defendand hold the PoP Parties harmless from and against any and all liability, losses, costs, and expenses(including attorneys’ fees) incurred by any PoP Party in connection with any claim, including, but notlimited to, claims for defamation, violation of rights of publicity and/or privacy, copyright infringement, ortrademark infringement arising out of your use of the Website; any use or alleged use of your accounts oryour passwords by any person, whether or not authorized by you; Your Content; your connection to theWebsite; your violation of this Policy; or your violation of the rights of any other person or entity.

We reserve the right, at our own expense, to assume the exclusive defense and control of any matter forwhich you are required to indemnify us, and you agree to cooperate with our defense of these claims.

Termination. PoP may suspend or terminate any user’s access to all or part of the Website without noticeor recourse, for any conduct that PoP, in its sole discretion, believes is in violation of any applicable law orof this Policy or is harmful to the interests of another user, a service provider, PoP or its affiliates.

Governing Law. By visiting or using the Website and/or by submitting Your Content, you agree that thelaws of the State of New York, without regard to principles of conflicts of law, will govern this Policy andany dispute of any sort that might arise between you and PoP. You agree that any action at law or inequity that arises out of or relates to any use of the Website will be filed only in the state or federal courtslocated in New York County and you hereby consent and submit to the personal jurisdiction of suchcourts for the purposes of litigating any such action.

Site Directed at United States Visitors. The Website is targeted at and intended for users residing in theUnited States. Given the global nature of the Internet and PoP’s services, the Website may be accessedby users residing outside of the United States. We make no representations or warranties that theWebsite is appropriate or available for use in countries outside of the United States. Users who choose toaccess the Website from outside of the United States do so at their own initiative and are responsible forcompliance with any and all local laws and regulations that may apply to such access. If you are locatedoutside of the United States, your Information will be transferred to the United States. By accessing theWebsite and by submitting your Information, you consent to its transfer and storage in the United Statesand its use by us as provided for herein.

Children Under the Age of 13. We are pleased when young people visit the Website to learn aboutPoP and how they can help. We are also concerned about the privacy protection of children who accessthe Internet, and we comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). Accordingly, theWebsite is not intended for use by anyone under the age of 13 without the supervision of a parent orguardian, and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under 13 yearsof age) without the consent of parent or guardian. If you are under the age of 13 (or otherwise under theapplicable age limit of your country), please do not submit any personally identifiable information to us.You may rely on your parent or guardian to assist you. If you are a parent of a child under the applicableage limit for consent in your country and become aware that your child has provided Information to us,please contact us by email at info@pencilsofpromise.org so that we can either (a) gain your consent tothe collection of the Information or (b) receive your instructions to delete the Information. If we learn thatwe have collected Information from a child without the consent of a parent or guardian, we will take allreasonable steps to delete the Information in the absence of contrary written instruction from such parentor guardian.

Changes to this Privacy Policy. When we make material changes to this Policy, we will provide you withnotice as appropriate under the circumstances by displaying a prominent notice within the Website or bysending you an email (if we have your email address). We may notify you in advance. Please be sure toread any such notice carefully. You can tell that this Policy has been updated by checking the last reviseddate posted on the top of this page. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changesto this Privacy Policy will mean that you accept those changes.

How You Can Update or Correct Your Information and Contact Us. You can contact us at any time byphone, email or mail at the numbers and addresses provided below if you have any questions or concernsregarding the Website or this Policy, or wish to seek access to, update, correct, or delete your Information.

Pencils of Promise, Inc.1115 Broadway, Suite 1157

New York, NY 10010

(212) 777-3170

info@pencilsofpromise.org
